Guide to the United Railroads of San Francisco Records, 1866-1951
Department of Special Collections
United Railroads of San Francisco Records,
1866-1951
Special Collections M161
United Railroads of San Francisco
19 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions:
None.
Provenance:
Found among the Hopkins Transportation Library manuscripts.
Historical Note
The United Railroads of San Francisco, as well as the Market Street Railway Company and the Municipal Railway Co., were all aggregations of smaller street railway lines that provided urban transportation for San Francisco. Among these street railways were the following: Sutter Sreet Railway Co., Sutro Railway Co., San Francisco & Alameda R.R. Co., and the South San Francisco Railroad and Power Co.
The United Railroads of San Francisco was organized in March, 1902, with authorized capital stock of 40 million dollars mostly owned by California Rail & Power Co. Because of its inability to pay matured indebtedness and interest on outstanding indebtedness, it sold out to Market Street Cable Railway Co. in 1921. In 1944, the Municipal Railway of San Francisco (Muni) bought the capital of the Market Street Railway Co.
Scope and Content
The collection includes record books, business and legal papers, financial papers, clippings, stock records, statistics, ledgers, and so forth, of the above railway companies. It also includes annual reports of the Municipal Railway Co. for the years 1949-50 and 1950-51.
Added Entries
Market Street Railway Co.; Sutter Street Railway Co.; South San Francisco Railroad and Power Co.; San Francisco and Alameda Railroad Co.; Sutro Railway Co.; San Francisco Electric Railroad.; San Francisco Municipal Railway.; San Francisco and San Mateo Railway Co.
Container List
- United Railroads of San Francisco
  - Daily Records of Passenger Earnings, March, 1907 -September, 1907. (Volume 1)
  - Daily Records of Passenger Earnings, October, 1907 -March, 1908. (Volume 2.)
  - Daily Records of Passenger Earnings, April, 1908 -September, 1908. (Volume 3.)
  - Daily Records of Passenger Earnings, October, 1910 -March, 1911. (Volume 4.)
  - Daily Records of Passenger Earnings, April, 1911 -September, 1911. (Volume 5.)
  - Daily Records of Passenger Earnings, October, 1911 -March, 1912. (Volume 6.)
  - Daily Records of Passenger Earnings, April, 1912 -September, 1912. (Volume 7.)
  - Daily Records of Passenger Earnings, October, 1912 -March, 1913. (Volume 8.)
  - Daily Records of Passenger Earnings, April, 1913 -September, 1913. (Volume 9.)
  - Daily Records of Passenger Earnings, October, 1913 -April, 1914. (Volume 10)
  - Daily Records of Passenger Earnings, April, 1914 -September, 1914. (Volume 11.)
  - Daily Records of Passenger Earnings, October, 1914 -March, 1915. (Volume 12)
  - Daily Records of Passenger Earnings, April, 1915 -September, 1915. (Volume 13.)
  - Daily Records of Passenger Earnings, September, 1915 -December, 1915. (Volume 14.)
  - Daily Records of Passenger Earnings, July, 1916 -December, 1916 (Volume 15.)
  - Daily Records of Passenger Earnings, January, 1919 -June, 1919. (Volume 16.)
  - Recapitulation, 1903 -1920. (Volume 17.)
  - Monthly record, 1903 -1918. (Volume 18.)
  - Daily Records of Passenger Earnings, January, 1924 -June, 1924. (Volume 19.)
  - Outstanding first preferred stock dividend warrants, series A - F, odd share certificates. (Volume 20.)
  - Outstanding first preferred stock dividend warrants, series A - X, 10 share certificates. (Volume 21.)
  - First preferred stock, # 1 - 250. (Volume 22.)
  - a) Common stock, # 1 - 250. (Box 23.)
  - b) Plan for reorganization, 1916 -1920. (Box 23.)
  - c) Lawyer's register of actions (1908 -1910). (Box 23.)
  - d) Register of (court) actions (1910 -1911). (Box 23.)
  - e) Diary of Court Actions, 1908. (Box 23.)
  - f) Ford King reminiscence of employment, 1904 -1907. (Box 23.)
  - Legal files regarding damage suits (1906 -1909). (Box 24-25.)
  - Diaries of Court Actions, 1911, 1917, 1919 & 1920. Platform men entering and leaving service, 1908. (Box 26.)
  - Supplemental Reports, earnings and other related financial information, 1905 -1914. (Box 27.)
  - Clippings, strike of 1917. (Volume 28.)
  - U.R.R. of S.F. Time sheets, 1908. (Volume 29-31.)
  - (Engineer's) Report, part II, 1905,includes Market Street Railway Co., Sutter St. Railway Co., San Francisco and San Mateo Electric Railway Co., Sutro Railway Co., South San Francisco Railroad and Power Co., and other subsidiary companies. (Volume 32.)
- MARKET STREET RAILROAD
  - Stock ledger (1894 -1899). (Volume 33.)
  - Stock ledger, A - L, 1900 -1902. (Volume 34.)
  - Stock ledger, M - Z, 1900 -1902. (Volume 35.)
  - Stock and Transfer book (1893 -1898). (Volume 36.)
  - Stock transfer book (1899 -1902). (Volume 37.)
  - Legal diaries, 1917, 1918 & 1922. (Volume 38-40.)
  - 1) Market Street payroll, 1938. 2) Report on Present Value, 1942. 3) Report on Results of Operation, 1922-1942. 4) Tables & Charts re: Manpower and Service, 1943. (Volume 41.)
- SUTTER STREET RAILWAY COMPANY
  - Cash Journal, 1909 -1924. (Volume 42.)
  - Vouchers entered, 1902. (Volume 43.)
- SOUTH SAN FRANCISCO RAILROAD & POWER CO.
  - Journal, 1904 -1923. (Volume 44.)
  - Voucher records, 1904 -1923. (Volume 45.)
- SAN FRANCISCO AND ALAMEDA RAILROAD CO.
  - Journal, 1866 -1868. (Volume 46.)
- SAN FRANCISCO ELECTRIC RAILROAD
  - Cash, 1909 -1921. (Volume 47.)
  - Journal., 1909 -1921. (Volume 48.)
  - "PAY AS YOU ENTER" ledger (no further identification). (Volume 49.)
  - Oversized volume. Samples of Southern Pacific stationary. (Volume 50.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: April, 1906 -August, 1906. (Volume 51.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: January -April, 1907. (Volume 52.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: June -September, 1908. (Volume 53.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: October -November, 1908(on cover, "MISCELLLANEOUS"). (Volume 54.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: March -November, 1909. (Volume 55.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: November, 1909 -April., 1910(on cover, "MISCELLLANEOUS") (Volume 56.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: January -May, 1909. (Volume 57.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: March, 1909 -August, 1911(on cover, "Patrick Calhoun"). (Volume 58.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: April -November, 1910. (Volume 59.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: November 1909 -January, 1910. (Volume 60.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: October -November, 1909(on cover, "Ford'). (Volume 61.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: April -June, 1910. (Volume 62.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: July -September, 1910. (Volume 63.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: February -March, 1911. (Volume 64.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: March -August, 1911. (Volume 65.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: September -November, 1911. (Volume 66.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: March -September, 1911(on cover, "Campaign of 1911"). (Volume 67.)
  - Clipping book prepared by the staff of the U.R. of S.F; subject emphasis: the graft trials: July, 1941 -January, 1942. (Volume 68.)
  - Misc. Purchase & Job Order Book, 1907. (Volume 69.)
- MUNICIPAL RAILWAY OF SAN FRANCISCO
  - Extracts from Mott Survey, 1931. (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Annual Report of Municipal Railway Co., Fiscal Year Ended June 30, 1950 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report of Municipal Railway Co., Fiscal Year Ended June 30, 1951 (Box 70, Folder 3)
- UNITED RAILROADS ARBITRATION
  - Transcript of Case Vol. 2. (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Transcript of Case Vol. 3. (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Transcript of Case Vol. 4. (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Transcript of Case Vol. 7. (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Transcript of Case Vol. 8. (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Transcript of Case Vol. 9. (Volume 72)